<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EXPLORE KARNATAKA</string>
    <string name="title_activity_netrani">netrani</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="netrani_txt">Netrani historically known as Bajrangi Island, Pigeon Island and also Heart Shaped Island is a small island of India located in the Arabian Sea. It is off the coast of Karnataka situated approximately 10 nautical miles (19 km) from the temple town of Murudeshwara in Bhatkal Taluka. The island can be seen from the mainland over 15 km (9.3 miles) away. Views above give this island the appearance of being heart-shaped. Its animal inhabitants include wild goats and pigeons.
        It has scuba diving facilities and is easily accessible from Bhatkal, Mangalore, Goa, Mumbai or Bangalore. There are dive shops at Murdeshwara and Goa which regularly organize trips to the island. It is known locally as Nitra Gudo. The famous Hindu temple Jai Bajrangbali Temple is located here., Netrani Island is one among the various unexplored places in Karnataka. Famous for diving/snorkelling, the heart-shaped island is known as Netragudo Island and Pigeon Island. With silvery sand and the Western Ghats as a backdrop, the island is accessible by a thrilling boat ride of 70-90 minutes. Known for its overwhelming experience of the underwater world, many varieties of aquatic species such as stonefish, black tip sharks, turtles, stingrays etc can be seen here. Certified divers of all experience levels can even try Scuba Diving here with the prices starting from INR 5,000.</string>
    <string name="teertha_txt">At a distance of 20 km from Hebri, 30 km from Agumbe, and 47 km from Udupi, Kudlu Teertha Falls is a picturesque waterfall located deep in the jungles of the Western Ghats near Hebri. Also known as Sita Falls, it is one of the most beautiful and most pristine falls in Karnataka and among the best places to visit near Agumbe as part of Udupi tour packages.
Located on Udupi-Agumbe Road, Kudlu Theertha is the first waterfall on the River Sita. It is a spectacular waterfall that drops from a height of about 300 feet into a pond. Legend has it that thousands of years ago sages used to meditate near the place where the pond exists today. As such, the local people consider the water of the pond to be very holy.
The pond where the water drops from the mountain is not very deep. Visitors can walk to a point where they can stand beneath the falling water and enjoy a refreshing bath. However, visitors need to exercise caution while putting their heads under a thick stream of water as the water drops down with immense force. Apart from waterfalls, the place is also known for its serene atmosphere. There is one more waterfall above Kudlu Theertha called Manga Theertha but there is no direct access to this fall.
Koodlu Theertha has remained as an isolated beauty that can only be reached by trekking through the dense forest. To reach the waterfall, trekkers have to cross the river Sita through a bridge built across it. The trek route penetrates further into the forest for about 4 km before it reaches a small stream. After crossing the stream and trekking for some more distance the fascinating Koodlu Theertha Falls unravels itself before the trekkers. Though the trek is a long and tiring one and passes through difficult terrain, the spectacular view of the waterfall rejuvenates trekkers and relieves them of their tiredness.
        Timings: 9 AM - 5 PM
Entry: Rs. 50 for Person</string>
    <string name="island_txt">At a distance of 15 km from Udupi Railway Station, 65 km from Mangalore and 100 km from Murudeshwar, St. Marys Island is a group of small beautiful islands situated to the north of Malpe Beach near Udupi. It is one of the best places to visit as part of Udupi Packages.
A quaint island just off the coast of Udupi, St. Mary Island is an island of white sand beaches, rock monoliths, and great wildlife making it one of the best places to visit in Udupi. It is said that Vasco da Gama first reached this Island before reaching the Kappad Beach (near Calicut) while finding a sea route to India.
This island is a group of four individual islands namely Coconut Island, North Island, South Island, and Daryabahadurgarh Island. The island has two beautiful beaches and crystallized basalt rock formations which were created at the time Madagascar Island got separated from India. These unique rock formations scattered throughout the island giving a special landscape to the place. Watching the sunset standing on the crystalline rocks is one of the most alluring experiences on the island.
St.MaryIsland is 4 miles away from the coast and can be reached by 30 minutes boat ride from Malpe Beach. This island is uninhabited and there is no possibility to stay overnight there.
Ferry Timings from Malpe: 9.30 AM - 5.30 PM,
        Closed from June - September
Entry Fee: Rs. 250 for Person,
        Rs. 200 for Camera and Rs. 250 - 300 for Ferry</string>
    <string name="konda_txt">At a distance of 500 m from Apsara Konda Bus Stop, 7 km from Honavar, 28 km from Kumta and 20 km from Murudeshwar, Apsara Konda Falls is a small waterfall located in the Uttara Kannada (North Canara) district of Karnataka. It is one of the scenic tourist places near Murudeshwar.
The water cascades down from a height of 10 meters into a pond below. The specialty of this pond is that it faces the sea and appears like a lagoon. People say that Angels used to come from heaven and take bath in that pond, hence the name Apsara Konda. Reaching the base of the waterfall is an easy as steps have been built to make the trail easier for the public. A unique fact about the waterfall is that the water flows down through the roots of a peepal tree while descending to the pond below. The pond is very safe for swimming and playing.
There is a beautiful temple - Umamba Maha Ganapathi and Ugra Narasimha Temple and a branch of Ramachandrapura Matt, Hosanagar. Other tourist attractions near to the falls are Kasarkod beach, Basavaraja Durga and Idagunji Maha Ganapathi Temple.
From Honavar there is bus facility to Apsara Konda but frequently is quite less. Better to go by own vehicle or hire a vehicle from Honavar. There is a signboard after Kasarkod to reach Apsara Konda. Visitors have to take turn from this signboard and the waterfall is about 1.5 km from here.
The best time to visit this falls is from October to February. </string>

    <string name="ermai_txt">At a distance of 5 km from Didupe, 18 km from Ujire, 19 km from Charmadi, and 89 km from Chikmagalur, Ermayi, or Ermai Falls is a mesmerizing waterfall situated near Kajoor in the Chikkamagaluru district of Karnataka. It is one of the lesser-known waterfalls in Karnataka, and among the best places to visit near Chikmagalur.
Ermai Waterfall is a hidden waterfall located at the foothills of the Ballalarayana Durga range of the Western Ghats. This is a multi-layered waterfall that slides down the rocky terrain from 75 feet. It forms a 5 feet deep pool at the bottom where tourists can swim or play with water. However, avoid getting too close to waterfalls during monsoon as the water level tends to increase along with strong currents. Do not climb without the guidance of locals or experienced trekkers as plenty of people have lost their life.
It is a seasonal waterfall, which comes to full glory in the peak monsoon season. The waterfall is situated on private property but the public can visit this place. In addition to this, there are 2 other waterfalls near Ermayi which can be trekked with the help of locals. This is a remote place so avoid getting into the jungle on yourself because it is very confusing to find a way out. Moreover, there are no eateries or restaurants in and around the corner, so it will be better to carry food.
To reach this place one can travel to Uijre, from there reach Mundaje, take the diversion towards Didupe village. After heading 6 km from there you get the point to take the route to Ermayi Falls, just before the Kajoor Dargah, on which four-wheelers can move for about a kilometer. One has to cross the Ermai stream thereafter and resort to trekking to cover the remaining stretch of about 1.5 km to reach the destination. While the stream can be negotiated by foot during the summer, one has to walk on the foot-bridge made of areca nut tree logs during the rainy season. There are no signboards to guide, so it is better to ask the locals or hire a guide for an accurate route.
Timings: 7 AM - 5 PM
Entry: Rs. 15 for Person </string>

</resources>